Subtitle Provide by dramacool.asia Translator [Admin.@YNG]
Subtitle Provide by dramacool.asia Translator [Admin.@YNG]
[The Journey of Legend]
[The Journey of Legend]
[Episode 24]
[Episode 24]
That day, Old Madam Wu gave me a dagger.
That day, Old Madam Wu gave me a dagger.
She said it was a gift from Mr. Zhang.
She said it was a gift from Mr. Zhang.
But I accidentally discovered
But I accidentally discovered
this crystal inside the dagger.
this crystal inside the dagger.
This crystal is the Hero Command Token.
This crystal is the Hero Command Token.
But I've been unable
But I've been unable
to figure out the mystery of the Voidheart Codex.
to figure out the mystery of the Voidheart Codex.
We've finally found the Hero Command Token,
We've finally found the Hero Command Token,
but it turns out the token actually doesn't contain the Voidheart Codex.
but it turns out the token actually doesn't contain the Voidheart Codex.
These 3 fingerprints
These 3 fingerprints
belong to Tianzheng from Shaolin Sect,
belong to Tianzheng from Shaolin Sect,
Taichan from Wudang Sect,
Taichan from Wudang Sect,
and Zhichen from Emei Sect.
and Zhichen from Emei Sect.
The only one still alive
The only one still alive
is Zhichen from Emei Sect.
is Zhichen from Emei Sect.
If we go to Emei Sect,
If we go to Emei Sect,
even if we don't find
even if we don't find
the Voidheart Codex's whereabouts,
the Voidheart Codex's whereabouts,
we might find clues about Crazy Yan.
we might find clues about Crazy Yan.
I've always felt that Crazy Yan
I've always felt that Crazy Yan
might be able to cure your father.
might be able to cure your father.
Besides,
Besides,
I once promised Old Madam Wu
I once promised Old Madam Wu
that I would find Crazy Yan's sister.
that I would find Crazy Yan's sister.
What's wrong?
What's wrong?
It's Tang Song.
It's Tang Song.
When I fell into the trap,
When I fell into the trap,
I sent a bee to follow him.
I sent a bee to follow him.
He's heading to Insect Valley now.
He's heading to Insect Valley now.
Is there something unusual about that?
Is there something unusual about that?
The once-every-5-years Night of Yin-Hai
The once-every-5-years Night of Yin-Hai
is about to begin.
is about to begin.
It's exactly at this time
It's exactly at this time
that other branches can challenge the first branch—
that other branches can challenge the first branch—
regardless of life or death.
regardless of life or death.
The winner will become the new leader of Tang Sect.
The winner will become the new leader of Tang Sect.
But this time, the place chosen for the Night of Yin-Hai
But this time, the place chosen for the Night of Yin-Hai
is actually Insect Valley.
is actually Insect Valley.
That's what I find suspicious.
That's what I find suspicious.
That is the forbidden area of Tang Sect.
That is the forbidden area of Tang Sect.
It's been a few years since it opened.
It's been a few years since it opened.
The Death Beetle King.
The Death Beetle King.
The rejuvenation place for it is Insect Valley.
The rejuvenation place for it is Insect Valley.
So he wants to use the Night of Yin-Hai to open Insect Valley.
So he wants to use the Night of Yin-Hai to open Insect Valley.
[Taoran Pavilion]
[Taoran Pavilion]
Big Brother,
Big Brother,
I heard you're going to see Sword King.
I heard you're going to see Sword King.
we still haven't found that whatever king.
we still haven't found that whatever king.
The Failure King.
The Failure King.
-Right, the Failure King. -Although we haven't found it,
-Right, the Failure King. -Although we haven't found it,
I will get
I will get
some evidence from Sword King.
some evidence from Sword King.
What do you need us to do?
What do you need us to do?
Don't worry.
Don't worry.
I'll get Sword King to leak some information to me.
I'll get Sword King to leak some information to me.
You guys, under the pretext of suppressing Liu Suifeng,
You guys, under the pretext of suppressing Liu Suifeng,
will actually weaken the Power Gang's strongholds.
will actually weaken the Power Gang's strongholds.
Count us sisters in.
Count us sisters in.
The Power Gang harmed our father. They're the Qu family's sworn enemies.
The Power Gang harmed our father. They're the Qu family's sworn enemies.
Now we are
Now we are
also members of the Shenzhou Sworn Brotherhood.
also members of the Shenzhou Sworn Brotherhood.
Big Brother, the Shenzhou Sworn Brotherhood
Big Brother, the Shenzhou Sworn Brotherhood
is growing stronger and stronger.
is growing stronger and stronger.
That's because of all of you.
That's because of all of you.
In the future, the Shenzhou Sworn Brotherhood
In the future, the Shenzhou Sworn Brotherhood
must restore peace to the martial world.
must restore peace to the martial world.
But everyone must remain vigilant.
But everyone must remain vigilant.
So we must strengthen our martial skills.
So we must strengthen our martial skills.
-Okay.
-Okay.
♪ Let this long river boil and burn ♪
♪ Let this long river boil and burn ♪
♪ Reforge new mountains and seas ♪
♪ Reforge new mountains and seas ♪
♪ Let the gleam of swords cut through all dust ♪
♪ Let the gleam of swords cut through all dust ♪
♪ Strive for the far shore at journey's end ♪
♪ Strive for the far shore at journey's end ♪
♪ Only when the long night finally comes to an end ♪
♪ Erst wenn die lange Nacht endlich zu Ende geht ♪
♪ Will this bow be not in vain ♪
♪ Wird diese Verbeugung nicht umsonst sein? ♪
♪ Let this long river boil and burn ♪
♪ Lass diesen langen Fluss kochen und brennen ♪
♪ Reforge new mountains and seas ♪
♪ Schmiede neue Berge und Meere ♪
♪ Let the gleam of swords cut through all dust ♪
♪ Lass den Glanz der Schwerter allen Staub durchschneiden ♪
♪ Strive for the far shore at journey's end ♪
♪ Strebe nach dem fernen Ufer am Ende der Reise ♪
♪ Only when the long night finally comes to an end ♪
♪ Erst wenn die lange Nacht endlich zu Ende geht ♪
♪ Will this bow be not in vain ♪
♪ Wird diese Verbeugung nicht umsonst sein? ♪
♪ Let the pouring rain drench me ♪
♪ Lass den strömenden Regen mich durchnässen ♪
♪ Let frost and snow embrace me too ♪
♪ Lass auch mich von Frost und Schnee umarmen ♪
♪ My lifelong sword intent remains unchanged ♪
♪ Meine lebenslange Schwertabsicht bleibt unverändert ♪
♪ Through 1,000 years, a million ages ♪
♪ Durch 1.000 Jahre, eine Million Zeitalter ♪
♪ I will still cleave mountains and carve paths ♪
♪ Ich werde weiterhin Berge spalten und Wege bahnen ♪
♪ Waiting for the fog to clear, waiting for the dawn and you to come ♪
♪ Ich warte darauf, dass sich der Nebel lichtet, ich warte auf die Morgendämmerung und auf dich ♪
Guys, please open Insect Valley's gate.
Leute, öffnet bitte das Tor zum Insektental.
Tonight is the Night of Yin-Hai.
Heute Nacht ist die Nacht von Yin-Hai.
We'll guard this place.
Wir werden diesen Ort bewachen.
Insect Valley has always been under my supervision.
Insect Valley stand immer unter meiner Aufsicht.
Why the change of personnel?
Warum der Personalwechsel?
You should ask the 5 elders about that.
Das sollten Sie die fünf Ältesten fragen.
Greetings, Elder Chijie.
Grüße, Ältester Chijie.
Greetings to the 4 elders of Success, Failure, Gain, Loss.
Grüße an die vier Ältesten des Erfolgs, des Misserfolgs, des Gewinns und des Verlusts.
This time's Night of Yin-Hai will take place in Insect Valley.
Dieses Mal findet die Nacht des Yin-Hai im Insektental statt.
We will replace all the guards of Insect Valley
Wir werden alle Wachen von Insect Valley ersetzen
with convicts sentenced to penal servitude in the Avici Tower.
mit zu Zwangsarbeit verurteilten Sträflingen im Avici-Turm.
This ensures impartiality and fairness toward all branches.
Dies gewährleistet Unparteilichkeit und Fairness gegenüber allen Zweigen.
Open the gate.
Öffne das Tor.
Take your men and leave.
Nehmen Sie Ihre Männer und gehen Sie.
Yes.
Ja.
Thank you, elders.
Danke, Älteste.
Please go and rest.
Bitte geh und ruh dich aus.
Master.
Master.
The guards here
Die Wachen hier
have all been replaced with our men.
wurden alle durch unsere Männer ersetzt.
Now you can go to the back valley without worry
Jetzt können Sie ohne Sorgen ins Hintertal gehen
to attend to your matters.
um Ihre Angelegenheiten zu erledigen.
No rush.
Keine Eile.
Is there something still troubling you?
Gibt es noch etwas, das Sie beunruhigt?
If I were Xiao Qiushui,
Wenn ich Xiao Qiushui wäre,
I would definitely come to Insect Valley today.
Ich würde heute auf jeden Fall ins Insect Valley kommen.
Guard this place carefully.
Bewachen Sie diesen Ort sorgfältig.
Yes.
Ja.
[Qu Residence]
[Qu-Residenz]
Mr. Xiao, have you found the Death Beetle King?
Herr Xiao, haben Sie den Todeskäferkönig gefunden?
No.
NEIN.
Why come to me without bringing what I asked for?
Warum kommst du zu mir, ohne das mitzubringen, worum ich gebeten habe?
I'm here...
Ich bin hier...
to save you.
um dich zu retten.
The molted shell of the Death Beetle King?
Die gehäutete Schale des Todeskäferkönigs?
Its 8 patterns are about to reduce to 7.
Die Zahl der 8 Muster wird sich bald auf 7 reduzieren.
Correct.
Richtig.
Now,
Jetzt,
the Power Gang uses Death Beetles in the Misery Pills
Die Power Gang verwendet Todeskäfer in den Misery Pills
to control others.
andere zu kontrollieren.
This Death Beetle King
Dieser Todeskäferkönig
is about to molt
steht kurz vor der Häutung
and urgently needs to rejuvenate.
und muss dringend verjüngt werden.
What does this have to do with me?
Was hat das mit mir zu tun?
Such an important thing—
So eine wichtige Sache –
Chief Li didn't entrust it to you.
Chef Li hat es Ihnen nicht anvertraut.
Instead, he gave this most trusted object
Stattdessen gab er dieses vertrauenswürdigste Objekt
to someone else.
an jemand anderen.
Think about it.
Denken Sie darüber nach.
If Liu Suifeng really succeeds in rejuvenating the Death Beetle King,
Wenn es Liu Suifeng wirklich gelingt , den Todeskäferkönig zu verjüngen,
he will become the new Blood Master.
er wird der neue Blutmeister.
The Misery Pills control so many people,
Die Misery Pills kontrollieren so viele Menschen,
including you, Sword King, right?
einschließlich dir, Schwertkönig, richtig?
You know everything?
Du weißt alles?
Above the Eight Kings of the Power Gang,
Über den Acht Königen der Power Gang,
all are controlled by the Misery Pills.
alle werden durch die Misery Pills kontrolliert.
The purpose
Der Zweck
is to prevent everyone from killing each other.
ist es, zu verhindern, dass sich alle gegenseitig umbringen.
If someone truly becomes the new Blood Master
Wenn jemand wirklich der neue Blutmeister wird
and breaks free from the control of the Misery Pill,
und befreit sich von der Kontrolle der Misery Pill,
guess
erraten
what would happen to those
was würde mit denen passieren
he bears a grudge against.
er hegt einen Groll gegen.
What do you intend to do?
Was haben Sie vor?
If Liu Suifeng
Wenn Liu Suifeng
accidentally kills one of the Eight Kings,
tötet versehentlich einen der Acht Könige,
the Misery Pill inside him will be activated.
die Misery Pill in ihm wird aktiviert.
Then he'll be severely weakened.
Dann wird er stark geschwächt sein.
At that time,
Damals,
both you and I can kill him.
sowohl Sie als auch ich können ihn töten.
Since we are to work together,
Da wir zusammenarbeiten sollen,
you must tell me
du musst es mir sagen
where his forces are located,
wo seine Streitkräfte stationiert sind,
so I can arrange
damit ich es arrangieren kann
to have them destroyed.
um sie zerstören zu lassen.
Then,
Dann,
you and I...
Du und ich...
Nice tea.
Guter Tee.
The entrance is right here.
Der Eingang ist gleich hier.
Okay.
Okay.
Wait.
Warten.
Who authorized you to guard the forbidden area?
Wer hat Sie ermächtigt , das verbotene Gebiet zu bewachen?
It was the elders' decision, of course.
Es war natürlich die Entscheidung der Ältesten.
It's the Night of Yin-Hai,
Es ist die Nacht von Yin-Hai,
yet the current Master didn't come.
doch der aktuelle Meister kam nicht.
There's no need
Es besteht keine Notwendigkeit
for my father to deal with you personally.
damit mein Vater sich persönlich um Sie kümmert.
Let us through now!
Lass uns jetzt durch!
Who gave you the nerve to act so recklessly?
Wer hat Ihnen die Frechheit gegeben , so rücksichtslos zu handeln?
If you're not convinced,
Wenn Sie nicht überzeugt sind,
why don't we have a match right now?
warum haben wir nicht gleich ein Match?
Bring it on.
Bring es an.
Old Madam Tang has arrived!
Die alte Madam Tang ist angekommen!
-Greetings, Old Madam Tang.
-Grüße, alte Madam Tang.
Coming this far is already annoying enough.
Es ist schon ärgerlich genug, so weit zu kommen .
Success, Failure, Gain, Loss, and Chijie,
Erfolg, Misserfolg, Gewinn, Verlust und Chijie,
the location for this Night of Yin-Hai—
der Ort für diese Nacht des Yin-Hai—
was it your idea?
war es deine Idee?
-Yes.
-Ja.
Never mind. Then let it begin quickly.
Macht nichts. Dann lass es schnell losgehen.
What's going on?
Was ist los?
Set the sedan down.
Setzen Sie die Limousine ab.
A stone came out of nowhere
Ein Stein kam aus dem Nichts
and injured my foot.
und habe mir den Fuß verletzt.
I startled Old Madam Tang.
Ich habe die alte Frau Tang erschreckt.
Please forgive me!
Bitte verzeihen Sie mir!
Enough. Have someone else take his place.
Genug. Lassen Sie jemand anderen seinen Platz einnehmen.
Yes.
Ja.
You.
Du.
Take his place.
Nehmen Sie seinen Platz ein.
Lift the sedan!
Heben Sie die Limousine an!
Set it down!
Leg es ab!
[Tang Sect's Old Madam Tang]
[Die alte Frau Tang der Tang-Sekte]
The night is deep and the dew is heavy.
Die Nacht ist tief und der Tau schwer.
This Night of Yin-Hai
Diese Nacht von Yin-Hai
will likely be a long one.
wird wahrscheinlich lang sein.
-Greetings, Old Madam Tang.
-Grüße, alte Madam Tang.
Xiao Qiushui has entered.
Xiao Qiushui ist eingetreten.
Don't let anyone enter the back valley.
Lassen Sie niemanden das hintere Tal betreten.
-Yes.
-Ja.
Tang Song
Tang Song
played so many tricks.
hat so viele Streiche gespielt.
I suspect there's a greater plot behind him.
Ich vermute, dass hinter ihm eine größere Verschwörung steckt.
You'll go to the Scorpion Platform.
Sie gelangen zur Scorpion-Plattform.
Be careful with everything.
Seien Sie bei allem vorsichtig.
The Night of Yin-Hai comes once every 5 years.
Die Nacht von Yin-Hai findet alle fünf Jahre statt.
After all these years, I'm used to it.
Nach all den Jahren bin ich daran gewöhnt.
If I can't even handle such a situation,
Wenn ich mit einer solchen Situation nicht einmal klarkomme,
how can I call myself a member of the first branch?
wie kann ich mich Mitglied des ersten Zweigs nennen?
Find a way to get to the back valley.
Finden Sie einen Weg, um ins hintere Tal zu gelangen.
Leave the rest to me.
Überlassen Sie den Rest mir.
Tang Song,
Tang Song,
it seems the other branches won't be coming up.
es scheint, dass die anderen Zweige nicht auftauchen werden.
It'll just be our first branch against your third branch.
Es wird einfach unsere erste Niederlassung gegen Ihre dritte Niederlassung sein.
Let's have a good fight.
Lasst uns einen guten Kampf haben.
Tang Qing,
Tang Qing,
aren't those two experts from the third branch?
sind das nicht zwei Experten aus der dritten Abteilung?
Why aren't they coming up to the Scorpion Platform?
Warum kommen sie nicht zur Scorpion-Plattform?
Tang Song,
Tang Song,
you guys still won't come up to the Scorpion Platform.
Ihr kommt immer noch nicht zur Scorpion-Plattform.
What tricks are you trying to play in front of Old Madam Tang?
Welche Streiche versuchen Sie vor der alten Frau Tang zu spielen?
Stop wasting time.
Verschwenden Sie keine Zeit mehr.
Tang Qing, you go first.
Tang Qing, du gehst zuerst.
Let's finish early so we can go back to rest.
Lasst uns früher fertig werden, damit wir uns wieder ausruhen können.
Yes.
Ja.
Fang, you're really eager to fight me.
Fang, du willst unbedingt gegen mich kämpfen.
Aren't you eager?
Bist du nicht gespannt?
Make your move.
Machen Sie Ihren Zug.
Deputy Chief Liu.
Stellvertretender Chef Liu.
This is the perfect place to nurture the Death Beetle King.
Dies ist der perfekte Ort , um den Todeskäferkönig aufzuziehen.
The miasma is thick, and fungi and grass grow abundantly.
Das Miasma ist dicht und Pilze und Gras wachsen im Überfluss.
Excellent.
Exzellent.
The moonlight has appeared.
Das Mondlicht ist erschienen.
I shall begin now.
Ich werde jetzt beginnen.
Guard the Beetle King well.
Beschütze den Käferkönig gut.
I'll eliminate any potential threats!
Ich werde alle potenziellen Bedrohungen beseitigen!
Ghost King.
Geisterkönig.
Qu Hanshan, you...
Qu Hanshan, du...
That's Chief's treasure.
Das ist der Schatz des Häuptlings.
Does Liu Suifeng want to keep it all for himself?
Will Liu Suifeng alles für sich behalten?
Qu Hanshan, this is Chief's order!
Qu Hanshan, das ist der Befehl des Chefs!
What if Liu Suifeng lied?
Was wäre, wenn Liu Suifeng gelogen hätte?
I think you'd better hand it over to me.
Ich denke, Sie sollten es mir lieber übergeben.
I'll go ask Chief.
Ich werde den Chef fragen.
If you interrupt its feeding, all our efforts will be wasted!
Wenn Sie die Fütterung unterbrechen, sind alle unsere Bemühungen umsonst!
If you won't hand it over,
Wenn Sie es nicht übergeben,
I'll have to borrow your body.
Ich muss mir deinen Körper ausleihen.
Xiao Qiushui,
Xiao Qiushui,
you think your 60 years of internal energy
Sie denken, Ihre 60 Jahre innere Energie
is enough to ambush me?
reicht aus, um mich zu überfallen?
As expected, we both came prepared.
Wie erwartet waren wir beide vorbereitet.
The disguise on our way into the valley just now
Die Verkleidung auf unserem Weg ins Tal gerade
was merely a show.
war nur eine Show.
Hiding from me
Versteckt sich vor mir
isn't your style.
ist nicht dein Stil.
Why don't you come out
Warum kommst du nicht raus
so we can talk properly?
damit wir richtig reden können?
Don't you want to know
Willst du nicht wissen
where your parents' bodies are?
wo die Leichen deiner Eltern sind?
I've treated them quite well.
Ich habe sie ziemlich gut behandelt.
To preserve their bodies from decay,
Um ihre Körper vor dem Verfall zu bewahren,
I've put in quite some effort.
Ich habe mir ziemlich viel Mühe gegeben.
But rest assured.
Aber seien Sie unbesorgt.
They're frozen quite solid.
Sie sind ziemlich fest gefroren.
Even striking them with a sword sheath couldn't bend them.
Selbst ein Schlag mit einer Schwertscheide konnte sie nicht verbiegen.
Though the sound was rather grating.
Allerdings war der Ton ziemlich schrill.
Ghost King?
Geisterkönig?
Tang Song,
Tang Song,
you can't defeat me.
du kannst mich nicht besiegen.
Qu Hanshan,
Qu Hanshan,
it's you.
du bist es.
You're clever indeed. You guessed it in one try.
Du bist wirklich clever. Du hast es auf Anhieb erraten.
I captured Ghost King, disguised him, and placed him here,
Ich habe Ghost King gefangen genommen, ihn verkleidet und hierher gebracht,
so you could kill the wrong person.
Sie könnten also die falsche Person töten.
You... actually worked with Xiao Qiushui.
Sie ... haben tatsächlich mit Xiao Qiushui zusammengearbeitet.
Why not?
Warum nicht?
By killing you,
Indem ich dich töte,
I can monopolize the gang's authority,
Ich kann die Autorität der Bande monopolisieren,
inherit the Death Beetle King,
erbe den Todeskäferkönig,
and control the entire martial world.
und die gesamte Kampfwelt kontrollieren.
This partnership suits me just fine.
Diese Partnerschaft passt mir sehr gut.
Song,
Lied,
this Death Bringer is forbidden in Tang Sect's internal conflicts.
Dieser Todesbringer ist in den internen Konflikten der Tang-Sekte verboten.
You can't use it.
Sie können es nicht verwenden.
Look!
Sehen!
This is...
Das ist...
Since the Night of Yin-Hai has begun, it must proceed.
Da die Nacht von Yin-Hai begonnen hat, muss sie weitergehen.
Tang Fang has won 4 matches in a row.
Tang Fang hat 4 Spiele in Folge gewonnen.
One more victory, and she'll remain the first branch.
Noch ein Sieg, und sie bleibt die erste Filiale.
Qu Hanshan,
Qu Hanshan,
you've been deceived by him!
du wurdest von ihm getäuscht!
Tang Song,
Tang Song,
you've lost.
du hast verloren.
Old Madam Tang,
Alte Frau Tang,
Tang Song used evil techniques to coerce the fifth branch.
Tang Song setzte bösartige Methoden ein , um den fünften Zweig zu zwingen.
Please be clear!
Bitte seien Sie deutlich!
-Punish Tang Song severely!
- Bestraft Tang Song streng! - Bestraft Tang Song streng!
He must be punished severely!
Er muss streng bestraft werden!
Old Madam Tang, Tang Song used gu insects to force us
Die alte Frau Tang, Tang Song, benutzte Gu-Insekten, um uns zu zwingen
to make Insect Valley the location for the Night of Yin-Hai.
um das Insektental zum Schauplatz der Nacht von Yin-Hai zu machen.
Then, using the 5 elders' authority over the Avici Tower,
Dann nutzte er die Autorität der fünf Ältesten über den Avici-Turm,
he replaced the guards here
er ersetzte hier die Wachen
with masked convicts.
mit maskierten Sträflingen.
Come here.
Komm her.
I'm Xiao Qiushui from Huanhua.
Ich bin Xiao Qiushui aus Huanhua.
Greetings, Old Madam Tang.
Grüße, alte Frau Tang.
So you're Xiao Qiushui.
Du bist also Xiao Qiushui.
But any outsider who disrupts Tang Sect's arena fight
Aber jeder Außenseiter, der den Arenakampf der Tang-Sekte stört
must pay with his life.
muss mit seinem Leben bezahlen.
Old Madam Tang, please be clear.
Alte Frau Tang, bitte seien Sie deutlich.
When Tang Song used the forbidden weapon,
Als Tang Song die verbotene Waffe benutzte,
the duel had already ended.
das Duell war bereits beendet.
Xiao Qiushui stepped in to aid me at that moment,
Xiao Qiushui eilte mir in diesem Moment zu Hilfe.
so no rules were broken.
es wurden also keine Regeln gebrochen.
Then how did he enter Insect Valley?
Wie gelangte er dann ins Insektental?
Fang, surely you weren't unaware, right?
Fang, das war dir doch sicher nicht entgangen, oder?
Old Madam Tang,
Alte Frau Tang,
entering Tang Sect's forbidden area is indeed my fault.
Das Betreten des verbotenen Bereichs der Tang-Sekte ist tatsächlich meine Schuld.
But Tang Sect's Tang Song conspired with the Power Gang
Aber Tang Song von der Tang-Sekte verschwor sich mit der Power Gang
to use Insect Valley to rejuvenate the gu insect.
Insect Valley zu verwenden, um das Gu-Insekt zu verjüngen.
I only came to stop it.
Ich bin nur gekommen, um es zu stoppen.
Now the Beetle King has been killed by me,
Nun wurde der Käferkönig von mir getötet,
and all infected Tang Sect members have recovered.
und alle infizierten Mitglieder der Tang-Sekte sind genesen.
I came to help Tang Sect
Ich bin gekommen, um der Tang-Sekte zu helfen
eliminate the traitors.
eliminiere die Verräter.
Tang Song!
Tang-Lied!
Is that so?
Ist das so?
Since we're not dead, we're the witnesses.
Da wir nicht tot sind, sind wir die Zeugen.
You'd better confess everything.
Du solltest besser alles gestehen.
I was so foolish
Ich war so dumm
that I was manipulated by the Power Gang.
dass ich von der Power Gang manipuliert wurde.
Old Madam Tang, spare me!
Alte Madam Tang, verschonen Sie mich!
Rare to see such a ruthless junior.
Es ist selten, einen so rücksichtslosen Junior zu sehen.
What a pity.
Wie schade.
Send Tang Song and all members of the third branch
Senden Sie Tang Song und alle Mitglieder des dritten Zweigs
to the Avici Tower!
zum Avici-Turm!
Old Madam Tang, spare me! No!
Alte Frau Tang, verschonen Sie mich! Nein!
-Old Madam Tang, spare me! -No!
-Alte Frau Tang, verschonen Sie mich! -Nein!
-Let me go! -Old Madam Tang, spare me!
-Lass mich gehen! -Alte Frau Tang, verschone mich!
Old Madam Tang! Old Madam Tang, spare me!
Alte Madam Tang! Alte Madam Tang, verschonen Sie mich!
-Old Madam Tang! Old Madam Tang! -Old Madam Tang, spare me!
-Alte Madam Tang! Alte Madam Tang! -Alte Madam Tang, verschonen Sie mich!
Old Madam Tang, I knew nothing about this.
Alte Frau Tang, ich wusste nichts davon.
I was deceived by Tang Song.
Ich wurde von Tang Song getäuscht.
Please believe me. Please believe me!
Bitte glauben Sie mir. Bitte glauben Sie mir!
Please believe me! Please believe me!
Bitte glauben Sie mir! Bitte glauben Sie mir!
The Avici Tower is harsh,
Der Avici-Turm ist hart,
but you don't have to kill yourself.
aber du musst dich nicht umbringen.
I'm innocent.
Ich bin unschuldig.
I'd rather die to prove my innocence.
Ich würde lieber sterben, um meine Unschuld zu beweisen.
If the third branch is completely gone, things would be less lively.
Wenn der dritte Zweig ganz wegfällt, wird es weniger lebendig.
Send her to my courtyard to do chores.
Schicken Sie sie in meinen Hof, um Aufgaben zu erledigen.
Thank you, Old Madam Tang. Thank you!
Danke, alte Frau Tang. Danke!
The third son from Huanhua,
Der dritte Sohn aus Huanhua,
Xiao Qiushui, right?
Xiao Qiushui, richtig?
Yes.
Ja.
You came to my place and caused chaos.
Du bist zu mir gekommen und hast Chaos verursacht.
If I just let this go,
Wenn ich das einfach loslasse,
wouldn't Tang Sect
würde nicht Tang Sekte
lose a great deal of face?
viel Gesicht verlieren?
Old Madam Tang,
Alte Frau Tang,
-he... -Fang.
-er... -Fang.
Bringing an outsider into Tang Sect without permission is a grave offense too.
Es ist ebenfalls ein schweres Vergehen , einen Außenstehenden ohne Erlaubnis in die Tang-Sekte aufzunehmen.
Guards,
Wachen,
send Tang Fang to the Avici Tower as well!
schicke auch Tang Fang zum Avici-Turm!
Yes.
Ja.
Old Madam Tang,
Alte Frau Tang,
why must you do this?
warum musst du das tun?
Earlier, when the Power Gang's demon recognized me,
Vorhin, als der Dämon der Power Gang mich erkannte,
you sent someone to help me out of that situation.
Sie haben jemanden geschickt , der mir aus dieser Situation hilft.
With Insect Valley being the location for the Night of Yin-Hai,
Da das Insektental der Ort für die Nacht von Yin-Hai ist,
you knew something would go wrong,
Sie wussten, dass etwas schiefgehen würde,
yet you didn't stop Tang Song.
dennoch hast du Tang Song nicht aufgehalten.
Those contradictory actions
Diese widersprüchlichen Aktionen
were deliberately planned by you, right?
wurden von Ihnen absichtlich geplant, richtig?
Why would I do that?
Warum sollte ich das tun?
Because you wanted to clean house
Weil du aufräumen wolltest
without offending the Power Gang.
ohne die Power Gang zu beleidigen.
So you used me
Also hast du mich benutzt
to eliminate the wolves that invaded your home
um die Wölfe zu beseitigen , die in Ihr Haus eingedrungen sind
and incidentally exposed Tang Song.
und nebenbei Tang Song entlarvt.
If that's the case,
Wenn das der Fall ist,
Tang Fang didn't violate sect rules
Tang Fang hat die Sektenregeln nicht verletzt
by secretly bringing me into Tang Sect.
indem er mich heimlich in die Tang-Sekte brachte.
Rather, she understood your intentions
Vielmehr verstand sie deine Absichten
and acted in advance
und handelte im Voraus
to ease your burdens.
um Ihre Belastungen zu verringern.
I don't understand
Ich verstehe nicht
what you're saying.
was du sagst.
Xiao Qiushui, you entered Tang Sect without permission.
Xiao Qiushui, Sie haben die Tang-Sekte ohne Erlaubnis betreten.
If I simply let you leave Tang Sect,
Wenn ich dich einfach die Tang-Sekte verlassen lasse,
I'm afraid it would break our rules.
Ich fürchte, es würde gegen unsere Regeln verstoßen.
Xiao Qiushui,
Xiao Qiushui,
since you have Tang Sect's invitation token,
da du das Einladungs-Token der Tang-Sekte hast,
I will overlook today's offenses
Ich werde über die heutigen Vergehen hinwegsehen
by you and Tang Fang.
von dir und Tang Fang.
Since Tang Fang is innocent,
Da Tang Fang unschuldig ist,
the first branch remains the first branch!
der erste Zweig bleibt der erste Zweig!
After such a long night,
Nach so einer langen Nacht,
go back and rest early!
geh zurück und ruh dich früh aus!
Why didn't you dodge Old Madam Tang's strike?
Warum sind Sie dem Schlag der alten Frau Tang nicht ausgewichen ?
That strike
Dieser Streik
was a show for Tang Sect's members.
war eine Show für die Mitglieder der Tang-Sekte.
And it was meant to establish authority.
Und es sollte Autorität etablieren.
Of course I couldn't dodge it.
Natürlich konnte ich dem nicht ausweichen.
Are you alright?
Geht es dir gut?
I'm fine.
Mir geht es gut.
There's no time to waste.
Es gibt keine Zeit zu verlieren.
Let's leave quickly.
Lass uns schnell gehen.
I painstakingly planted Sword King,
Ich habe Sword King sorgfältig gepflanzt,
and he was actually removed just like that.
und er wurde tatsächlich einfach so entfernt.
[Sword King Qu Hanshan]
[Schwertkönig Qu Hanshan]
I underestimated you.
Ich habe dich unterschätzt.
Master!
Master!
Master, your injuries are severe. You need rest.
Meister, Ihre Verletzungen sind schwer. Sie brauchen Ruhe.
Don't force yourself to use your energy again.
Zwingen Sie sich nicht, Ihre Energie erneut zu verbrauchen.
Destroying my Death Beetle King
Zerstörung meines Todeskäferkönigs
and killing 2 kings in a row—
und zwei Könige hintereinander zu töten –
Xiao Qiushui killed 3 birds with 1 stone.
Xiao Qiushui hat drei Fliegen mit einer Klappe geschlagen.
What a vicious plot.
Was für eine bösartige Verschwörung.
Master,
Master,
should we tell Chief about this?
sollen wir dem Chief davon erzählen?
Liu Suifeng!
Liu Suifeng!
Liu Suifeng,
Liu Suifeng,
don't you think you owe us
meinst du nicht, du schuldest uns
an explanation today?
heute eine Erklärung?
Blade King,
Klingenkönig,
who gave you the nerve to disrespect the Deputy Chief?
Wer hat Ihnen die Frechheit verliehen , den stellvertretenden Chef zu missachten?
What are you all doing here uninvited?
Was macht ihr alle hier, ohne eingeladen zu sein?
Are you rebelling?
Rebellieren Sie?
I don't need to explain anything to you.
Ich muss Ihnen nichts erklären.
Liu Suifeng,
Liu Suifeng,
spare us your smooth talk.
ersparen Sie uns Ihr süßes Gerede.
The Eight Kings were established
Die Acht Könige wurden gegründet
to check your authority.
um Ihre Autorität zu überprüfen.
The gang has its rules.
Die Gang hat ihre Regeln.
Even if Chief lets you off today,
Selbst wenn der Chef Sie heute freilässt,
we will not let this go.
wir werden das nicht zulassen.
With the Misery Pills gone,
Da die Misery Pills weg sind,
you came to surround me without Chief's order.
Sie sind gekommen, um mich ohne den Befehl des Häuptlings zu umzingeln.
Are you respecting the gang's rules?
Respektieren Sie die Regeln der Gang?
They say you never miss a step,
Sie sagen, Sie verpassen nie einen Schritt,
yet you've failed repeatedly due to Xiao Qiushui.
dennoch sind Sie aufgrund von Xiao Qiushui wiederholt gescheitert.
Is your reputation
Ist Ihr Ruf
undeserved?
unverdient?
Or was it intentional?
Oder war es Absicht?
Why waste words on him?
Warum Worte über ihn verschwenden?
Let's just finish him
Lasst uns ihn einfach fertig machen
before his schemes cause more trouble.
bevor seine Pläne noch mehr Ärger verursachen.
Everyone, wait.
Alle warten.
I am at fault.
Ich bin schuld.
I will accept Chief's punishment.
Ich werde die Strafe des Chiefs akzeptieren.
But if anyone seeks to overstep his rank and plot a rebellion,
Wenn aber jemand versucht, seine Grenzen zu überschreiten und einen Aufruhr zu planen,
I still have the strength to clean house for Chief.
Ich habe immer noch die Kraft, für Chief aufzuräumen.
Who's rebelling?
Wer rebelliert?
We are unwaveringly loyal to Chief,
Wir sind dem Chef unerschütterlich treu,
but toward you, it's a different matter.
aber bei Ihnen ist das eine andere Sache.
You overstepped boundaries, and you're arrogant.
Sie haben Grenzen überschritten und sind arrogant.
Today, even if I die, I will punish you.
Heute werde ich dich bestrafen, selbst wenn ich sterbe.
This blade was made for you.
Diese Klinge wurde für Sie gemacht.
-Greetings, Chief.
-Grüße, Chef.
Suifeng's failure
Suifengs Scheitern
was due to Sword King's hidden disloyalty.
war auf die verborgene Illoyalität des Schwertkönigs zurückzuführen.
If anyone is to blame,
Wenn jemand schuld ist,
I should be blamed for focusing only on my own plans.
Man sollte mir vorwerfen, dass ich mich nur auf meine eigenen Pläne konzentriere.
Over the past few years,
In den letzten Jahren
I've neglected the private grudges brewing within our gang.
Ich habe die privaten Grollgefühle vernachlässigt, die in unserer Gang aufkamen.
That has allowed others to exploit
Das hat anderen erlaubt, auszunutzen
our internal conflicts to cause trouble.
unsere inneren Konflikte verursachen Ärger.
The Misery Pills
Die Elendspillen
were meant to prevent you from killing each other.
sollten verhindern, dass Sie sich gegenseitig umbringen.
But if they breed resentment,
Aber wenn sie Ressentiments hervorrufen,
I won't use them again.
Ich werde sie nicht wieder verwenden.
Today, regarding what I'm really up to,
Was ich heute wirklich vorhabe,
I do owe you all an explanation.
Ich schulde Ihnen allen eine Erklärung.
[Filial Piety and Etiquette]
[Kindespflicht und Etikette]
Father,
Vater,
Mother,
Mutter,
I've failed you.
Ich habe dich enttäuscht.
I still haven't been able to rebuild Huanhua.
Ich konnte Huanhua immer noch nicht wieder aufbauen.
I can't even protect the sword manual now.
Ich kann jetzt nicht einmal das Schwerthandbuch schützen.
How can I ever rebuild Huanhua?
Wie kann ich Huanhua jemals wieder aufbauen?
I'm useless.
Ich bin nutzlos.
Yiren.
Yiren.
Don't blame yourself too much.
Machen Sie sich nicht zu viele Vorwürfe.
Xueyu,
Xueyu,
the Nangong family came to provoke us.
die Familie Nangong kam, um uns zu provozieren.
Although with a sword in my hand,
Obwohl ich ein Schwert in der Hand habe,
I can do nothing.
Ich kann nichts tun.
I'm so useless.
Ich bin so nutzlos.
Now everyone is kicking us while we're down.
Jetzt treten alle auf uns ein, während wir am Boden liegen.
I'm afraid we can't even stay in Jindu anymore.
Ich fürchte, wir können nicht einmal mehr in Jindu bleiben.
But don't worry.
Aber keine Sorge.
Even if it costs me my life,
Auch wenn es mich mein Leben kostet,
I will protect you.
Ich werde dich beschützen.
Yiren,
Yiren,
you've borne so much for the Xiao family.
Sie haben so viel für die Familie Xiao ertragen.
I
ICH
also wish to rebuild Huanhua
auch wollen Huanhua wieder aufbauen
to comfort our parents' souls in heaven.
um die Seelen unserer Eltern im Himmel zu trösten.
I am...
Ich bin...
willing to marry Nangong Wushang.
bereit, Nangong Wushang zu heiraten.
No, Xueyu.
Nein, Xueyu.
You can't marry him for the sake of the sword manual.
Du kannst ihn nicht wegen des Schwerthandbuchs heiraten.
This is the only thing
Das ist das Einzige
I can do now.
Das kann ich jetzt tun.
[Memorial Tablet of My Father, Xiao Xilou Memorial Tablet of My Mother, Sun Huishan]
[Gedenktafel meines Vaters Xiao Xilou, Gedenktafel meiner Mutter Sun Huishan]
I can never repay Father and Mother for raising me.
Ich kann meinem Vater und meiner Mutter nie zurückzahlen, dass sie mich großgezogen haben.
I am willing to marry Nangong Wushang
Ich bin bereit, Nangong Wushang zu heiraten
to repay the Xiao family and our parents
um die Familie Xiao und unsere Eltern zurückzuzahlen
with my life.
mit meinem Leben.
After all, you did take a palm strike.
Immerhin hast du einen Handflächenschlag erlitten.
Don't ignore it.
Ignorieren Sie es nicht.
This medicine can help you recover.
Dieses Arzneimittel kann Ihnen bei der Genesung helfen.
Thank you.
Danke schön.
Why aren't you sitting?
Warum sitzt du nicht?
Here.
Hier.
I already told you
Ich habe es dir schon gesagt
to rest properly,
um richtig auszuruhen,
yet you insisted on coming all the way out here.
und trotzdem bestanden Sie darauf, den ganzen Weg hierher zu kommen.
I won't go far.
Ich werde nicht weit gehen.
Don't worry, Doctor Tang.
Machen Sie sich keine Sorgen, Doktor Tang.
Can you stop pulling a long face like an eggplant?
Können Sie aufhören, ein langes Gesicht zu ziehen wie eine Aubergine?
I can't believe you.
Ich kann dir nicht glauben.
Big Brother.
Großer Bruder.
Seems like we came at a bad time.
Scheint, als wären wir zu einem ungünstigen Zeitpunkt gekommen.
I'm parched.
Ich bin ausgetrocknet.
Did you put sugar in this tea?
Haben Sie Zucker in diesen Tee getan?
And you put a lot in it.
Und Sie haben viel hineingesteckt.
It's making my teeth ache.
Meine Zähne tun davon weh.
Qiu,
Qiu,
your zither looks pretty nice.
deine Zither sieht sehr schön aus.
How about we brothers play a piece together?
Wie wäre es, wenn wir Brüder zusammen ein Stück spielen?
What's wrong with you?
Was ist los mit dir?
Him?
Ihn?
Our famously charming Mr. Zuoqiu
Unser berühmt charmanter Herr Zuoqiu
might soon be saying goodbye to his carefree playboy days.
könnte sich bald von seinen unbeschwerten Playboy-Tagen verabschieden .
You're reluctant, huh?
Sie sind zurückhaltend, was?
I thought I could outdrink Qu Mushuang.
Ich dachte, ich könnte mehr trinken als Qu Mushuang.
I planned to tell her after winning
Ich hatte vor, es ihr nach dem Gewinn zu sagen
that it's not her younger sister I like.
dass es nicht ihre jüngere Schwester ist, die ich mag.
The one I like is her.
Diejenige, die ich mag, ist sie.
This is too complicated.
Das ist zu kompliziert.
Although I practice the Joint Lock,
Obwohl ich den Joint Lock übe,
my master once told me
mein Meister hat mir einmal gesagt
that the Qu family's best technique, Spring Night,
dass die beste Technik der Familie Qu, Spring Night,
resembles the thread-twining joint lock,
ähnelt dem Faden-Gelenkschloss,
soft as a spring breeze entering dreams.
sanft wie eine Frühlingsbrise, die in Träume eindringt.
It breaks moves quietly,
Es bricht Bewegungen leise ab,
and its grace is unmatched in this world.
und seine Anmut ist auf dieser Welt unübertroffen.
I didn't believe it
Ich habe es nicht geglaubt
until that day Qu Mushuang drew her sword to save me.
bis zu jenem Tag, als Qu Mushuang ihr Schwert zog, um mich zu retten.
Only then did I realize
Erst dann wurde mir klar
that all the sword techniques I've ever seen
dass alle Schwerttechniken, die ich je gesehen habe
can't compare to those Qu Mushuang displayed
kann nicht mit denen verglichen werden, die Qu Mushuang gezeigt hat
to save me.
um mich zu retten.
If that's the case, why don't you
Wenn das der Fall ist, warum gehst du nicht
just tell Mushuang directly?
Sagen Sie es Mushuang einfach direkt?
Qu Mushuang is stubborn and protective of those close to her.
Qu Mushuang ist stur und beschützt die Menschen, die ihr nahe stehen.
Now Qu Minmiao likes Chaoran.
Jetzt mag Qu Minmiao Chaoran.
If Chaoran tells Qu Mushuang
Wenn Chaoran Qu Mushuang erzählt
that she's the one he likes,
dass sie diejenige ist, die er mag,
I'm worried that Qu Mushuang
Ich mache mir Sorgen, dass Qu Mushuang
might cut ties with Chaoran completely.
könnte die Verbindung zu Chaoran vollständig abbrechen.
Miss Tang is right.
Frau Tang hat Recht.
Qiu,
Qiu,
you should
Du solltest
say it clearly to them in the first place.
sagen Sie es ihnen von Anfang an deutlich.
Do you understand?
Verstehst du?
Qiushui, I'm back!
Qiushui, ich bin zurück!